(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] In this example, we are building the same
to do list application with the following features:
so we can add new items to the list,
we can cross items of the list,
and then decide to delete the one
that are no longer necessary.
We also have the option to filter and then display
only the ones that are completed
or uncheck to display them all.
So here the task will be to break up the UI.
We're going to divide the user interface into small units
following the powerful model of composition.
And this will help to organize the code more efficiently.
This will help to scale easily
and also to improve the maintainability and performance.
And part of the process will also to break
up the state management into small independent object
called atoms that you're going to find inside this directory
in the starter project.
So, I decided to move them in their separate file
in order to make them accessible from everywhere.
So as a reminder, the atoms are independent objects
that are used to contain pieces of state.
Then you have the selectors that are derived data created
from existing state and then let's go back to the app.js.
You're going to see that we use several hooks from the recall
API, and we're going to use them to read and update the state
from the components.
And so part of the exercise was also to create small units
which I have already done for the form and the list.
And actually you're going to find them right here.
So this is already here available
as small independent units,
right here and you see that we are sharing the states,
bypassing the props.
But this is not the way that we want to handle things.
Ultimately, we want to allow every component to subscribe
to the state changes independently
by subscribing to the atoms.
So now the challenge will be for you
to complete the following task.
So this part of creating functional, small, independent
component is already done.
The part, the next part will be for you
to allow every component to subscribe to the state changes
by accessing the atoms and selectors.
And you're going to have access here to the API reference
of recoil to see the different hooks that you can use
in order to read and update the state
from the components directly.
So here, the purpose, the goal is not to keep the state
here, the state management at the top level
from one location only.
So, we are meant to remove all of that
for the next part of the challenge.
So we're going to see the solutions together in the next video
in order to optimize this application.